Brandon Amos

(540) 947 1238 • ☑ bamos@cs.cmu.edu • ☑ bamos.github.io
in bdamos • ☑ brandondamos • ⑤ bamos
Generated on October 17, 2016

About

I am a third-year Computer Science Ph.D. student at Carnegie Mellon University. I work with Zico Kolter on machine learning and optimization and am supported by an NSF graduate research fellowship. I am particularly interested in improving our understanding of important modeling problems in computer vision, language, and reinforcement learning through the use of deep learning, optimization (sometimes convex), theory, and statistics.

Aug 2014 - Present

o Ph.D. in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University

Education

 M.S. in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University B.S. in Computer Science, Virginia Tech (3.99/4.00) Northside High School (Roanoke, Virginia) 	Aug 2014 – May 2016 Aug 2011 – May 2014 May 2011
Research Experience	., .
 Carnegie Mellon University, Prof. Zico Kolter Machine learning and optimization 	Apr 2016 – Present
 Carnegie Mellon University, Prof. Mahadev Satyanarayanan Machine learning, computer vision, and mobile computing 	Aug 2014 – Apr 2016
Virginia Tech, Prof. Jules WhiteMobile computing, cyber-physical systems, and security	May 2012 – May 2014
 Virginia Tech, Prof. Layne Watson Scientific computing, global/stochastic optimization, and bioinforma 	Jan 2013 – May 2014 atics
Virginia Tech, Prof. Binoy RavindranHeterogeneous compilers	Nov 2012 – Mar 2014

Selected Publications

- [1] **B. Amos**, L. Xu, J. Z. Kolter, "Input convex neural networks," *ArXiv preprint arXiv:1609.07152*, 2016. [Online]. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.07152.
- [2] H. Zhao, T. Adel, G. Gordon, B. Amos, "Collapsed Variational Inference for Sum-Product Networks," in ICML, 2016. [Online]. Available: http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~hzhao1/papers/ ICML2016/BL-SPN-main.pdf.
- [3] **B. Amos**, B. Ludwiczuk, M. Satyanarayanan, "Openface: A general-purpose face recognition library with mobile applications," Technical Report CMU-CS-16-118, CMU School of Computer Science, Tech. Rep., 2016. [Online]. Available: http://reports-archive.adm.cs.cmu.edu/anon/anon/2016/CMU-CS-16-118.pdf.
- [4] **B. Amos**, D. Easterling, L. Watson, W. Thacker, B. Castle, M. Trosset, "QNSTOP-QuasiNewton Algorithm for Stochastic Optimization," 2014. [Online]. Available: https://vtechworks.lib.vt.edu/bitstream/handle/10919/49672/qnTOMS14.pdf.

Teaching Experience

 Distributed Systems (CMU 15-440/640), TA 	S2016
 Software Design and Data Structures (VT CS 2114), TA 	S2013

Industry Experience

Data Scientist Intern, Adobe Research	May 2014 – Aug 2014
 Software Engineer Intern, Snowplow Analytics 	Dec 2013 – Jan 2014
 Software Engineer Intern, Qualcomm 	May 2013 – Aug 2013
 Software Engineer Intern, Phoenix Integration 	May 2012 – Aug 2012
 Network Administrator Intern, Sunapsys 	Jan 2011 – Aug 2011

Honors & Awards

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship	2016 - 2019
o 1st Place Undergraduate Senior Capstone Award, Virginia Tech Computer Scie	ence 2014
 David Heilman Research Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science 	2014
 Senior Scholar Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science 	2014
 Honorable Mention, CRA Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Award 	2014
 Awarded eight undergraduate merit scholarships 	2011 - 2014

Skills

Languages	Bash, C, C++, CSS, Fortran, Haskell, HTML, Java, JavaScript, LATEX, Lua,
	Make, Mathematica, Python, R, Scala
Frameworks	Akka, Android SDK/NDK, Caffe, Node.js, NumPy, TensorFlow, Torch7, Pandas,
	SciPy, scikit-learn, Spark, Spray
Systems	Linux, OSX